<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Sabu Siyad</title>
    <subtitle>Sabu Siyad&#x27;s Personal Website</subtitle>
    <link href="https://ssiyad.com/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://ssiyad.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2023-01-28T01:35:30.805276+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://ssiyad.com/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Retrospect</title>
        <published>2023-01-28T01:35:30.805276+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-01-28T01:35:30.805276+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://ssiyad.com/blog/retrospect/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://ssiyad.com/blog/retrospect/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Would you prefer if people only talked about the necessary bits, leaving any
emotion out of it? Regardless of your answer, it is most effective communication
method I know. Things could be very straightforward and clear, removing any
cloud of doubt in the message. This combined with logical reasoning might the
best ever form of communication we are capable of. Does this mean a perfect
human is one without emotions? Doesn’t it mean we will achieve greater
efficiency and success with it?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it also means we lose apathy right? What new heighs are we going climb
without it? Why are we climbing anyways? Why not just enjoy it from the valley?
This reminds me of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;title&#x2F;tt0238380&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Equilibrium&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Nice
Movie. Would recommend.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-we-die-for&quot;&gt;What do we die for?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am one of those who seek the meaning of life. People believe in different
things. Some strive for eternal paradise, some for peace and some for whatever
niceties they can get before and after death. Death was always interesting for
me. Maybe because dearest people died in front of me. Did they have something to
tell me, after they were dead? Or were they just, dead? I don’t know. What I
know is that there isn’t much for me the grand scheme of things. There is
probably no purpose to my life. There is (probably) nothing that awaits me after
death. It is said that the lifetime of a universe is the time of breath cycle of
Brahma, and we are so in-significant that the next universe will be created
right after.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think anything eternal will eventually become boring. I love to drive, but
driving forever is a punishment. Same for my favourite
snack&#x2F;game&#x2F;movie&#x2F;paradise. Maybe eternal hell will be boring as well&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;night&quot;&gt;Night&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Night is special for me. Earth (I never been outside so can’t talk about other
planets) is so much more enjoyable without the light of sun. Everything comes to
life at night. There is a certain beauty to the darkness that it becomes so
possessive at times.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: I was nicknamed &lt;em&gt;owl&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in high school&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;football-malayalam-pntuklli&quot;&gt;Football (Malayalam: പന്തുകളി)&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Kerala (Malabar) has a special festival that happens mostly in winter.
It is called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Sevens_football&quot;&gt;sevens football&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
tournaments. Trust me, we love football. But we also love to butcher it. If you
know football, you know it is (officially) played with 11 players on each team.
But we play it with 7 on each. Matches are extremely physical, and are played in
a mud pitch. Venues are usually wide fields (we have a lot of paddy fields) or
school grounds. They may not have the necessary infrastructure, hence everything
is built temporarily, using arecanut tree, including the gallery. The atmosphere
is usually electric, sometimes violent, and rarely chaotic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a while since I went to one of these events. Past week, me and a
friend very accidentally got into one. We were out for our usual evening walk,
and saw fireworks from distance. I knew about the event and we decided to check
it out. By the team we reached there, it was already half time. I was not really
interested in getting in. Mostly because I unknowingly developed this football
elitism, in which only higher tier (read English Premier League) football is
considered actual. All other forms are seen as disgraces. But as you may have
imagined, we finally got in. This happened because of two things&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There was nobody to check tickets&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The atmosphere suddenly became so loud (became interesting)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;media&#x2F;blog&#x2F;retrospect&#x2F;football.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;football&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo from Google. I was too immersed to click a picture&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did not know which teams were playing, or at what time this will end. Any of
decision is immediately followed by a regret check. I don’t regret any of it,
but sometimes make changes to catch up. In this case, I felt like I am alone in
a crowd (friend beside me), and it wouldn’t be false to say I considered
leaving. After a while though, I found myself cheering both teams. I cussed at
both teams, and found home in both teams. These tournaments import a lot of
manpower from african continent. They don’t understand the local language, nor
does locals understand them. But in the heat of the moment, everybody understand
everybody else. I could read their happiness, curses, antics and whatnot without
any words. I know they were not teaching quantum physics in that football field,
but I felt emotions are as powerful as words.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unexpressed emotions will never die. They are buried alive and will come forth
later in uglier ways. - Sigmund Freud&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;kathakali-malayalam-kthklli&quot;&gt;Kathakali (Malayalam: കഥകളി)&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Kathakali&quot;&gt;Kathakali&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (katha: story, kali: play)
is a classical dance form native to (Southern) Kerala. It is boring, not at all
engaging and you need to have a lot of knowledge to even understand what is
going on. The pace is usually extremely slow and it takes forever to finish.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched kathakali before, but as part of school and college art festivals. But
that is not why we (or me) attend such events. The blood brooding youth does not
usually show interest in such art. Long story short, even though it is very
popular in my state, I had no idea what it actually is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me and friend were out for some shopping. And while passing a temple, we heard
some music. On the way back, curious to know what was happening there, we went
in. Unsurprisingly, it was kathakali. Now you know I don’t like it, but decided
to give it a try. We spent about 2 hours there, and realized&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’m not in school&#x2F;college anymore&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don’t understand a thing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third point must be obvious. You have to have some knowledge about the story
that is being presented. I don’t have any such knowledge, and didn’t understand
a thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kathakali actors don’t speak (the speak a sign language tbf), they only act.
There is supposed to be a song in background iirc, but wasn’t that case here.
I might be wrong tho. Maybe we need words to effectively communicate&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;media&#x2F;blog&#x2F;retrospect&#x2F;kathakali.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;kathakali&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sorry for poor quality, had to zoom in with a mobile camera&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was more invested in the music, acting and atmosphere. It was all dark except
for a few lamps in the building. There was a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Nilavilakku&quot;&gt;traditional fire lamp&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
in front of the stage, and a few other lamps in the stage. It all means,
everything other than the stage&#x2F;actor was grayed out. So you could really
notice all the expressions and emotions on his face, and the accompanying music
amplified it the next level. Every bit of that music transferred his emotions
straight into my heart. I could feel the anger, panic and ultimately regret. It
made me so immersed that I could visualise the scene myself (not knowing the
story became a boon, because I now have the freedom to make up my own). It made
me think if sound&#x2F;atmosphere actually contribute to effective communications. My
answer would be yes, it does. Interestingly,
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theconversation.com&#x2F;whats-behind-the-obsession-over-whether-elizabeth-holmes-intentionally-lowered-her-voice-177961&quot;&gt;this&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
came into mind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;kantara&quot;&gt;Kantara&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might know &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;title&#x2F;tt15327088&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Kantara&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It tells the
story of a remote village and their traditions. I’m not a movie reviewer so I
can’t entertain you with all the technicalities. The movie did not impress me
much, except the rare occasions in which the demigod appears. I am not a
believer, so I won’t talk about god and stuff. What made it interesting is the
background score. It was so chilling and engaging that it conveyed the message
pretty well. But in the end, it is a movie and I’m watching it in air
conditioned cinema theater.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching kathakali though, is a very similar very different experience.
Everything felt hyper realistic, nerve chilling and engaging. Our ability to
communicate (universally) with slighter movements of muscles is fascinating. I
would recommend you to try any of these arts. There are plenty in our great
nation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-though&quot;&gt;Why though?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These events (with numerous others) taught me that we are, in the end, simply
live to live. It is hard to survive in a world where competition is in it’s
extreme. We often forget to enjoy the things around us. We miss the opportunity
to actually live instead of being in a rat race. I still don’t know the purpose
of life, but I now know there are places to go and things to do, starting from
home. Maybe we don’t need to be all logical. Some things don’t make sense at
all, but they still make you happy (how do you define happiness?). Maybe words
are not the basis of communication. Instead they could be tip of this iceberg.
With emotions deep under.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Which is more important,’ asked Big Panda, ‘the journey or the destination?’
‘The company,’ said Tiny Dragon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for bearing with me, adios!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Veronika Decides To Try JavaScript</title>
        <published>2022-08-23T20:52:29+05:30</published>
        <updated>2022-08-23T20:52:29+05:30</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://ssiyad.com/blog/veronika-decides-to-try-javascript/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://ssiyad.com/blog/veronika-decides-to-try-javascript/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That’s a joke, she didn’t. Instead, she decides to die only to meet a new world of infinite
possibilities that awaited her. She is a character from Paulo Coelho’s stellar novel titled
‘Veronika Decides to Die’. If you haven’t read it already, I suggest you do. It’s a good
book with a very much relatable setting. Meanwhile, I thought it might make a good title so
here we are.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking, what is this about then, if not Veronika? yes! it’s JavaScript! Even
tho I’m not a big fan of JavaScript, I find it quite tinker-able and useful. JavaScript
makes its way into almost everything, from front-end web development to smartphone
applications. If you’re one of those who use VSCode, your editor runs on JavaScript. If you
happen to use any cross-platform desktop applications, it is probably an electron app that
renders JavaScript in a polished window. That being said, if you’re a JavaScript guru,
please ignore the rest of this post, and wave your hands as you close this window. If
you’re going to continue reading, let me welcome you to the problem and the reasons for it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-backstory&quot;&gt;The Backstory&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;= &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;1
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;1
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;b &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;= &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;1
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;1
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;== &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;b
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;true
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is good, both &lt;code&gt;a&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; have a value of &lt;code&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and when we check if &lt;code&gt;a&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;
are equal (&lt;code&gt;==&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;), it returns &lt;code&gt;true&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; which means both &lt;code&gt;a&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; have equal values.
Let’s also note that,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; typeof &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;number&amp;#39;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; typeof &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;b
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;number&amp;#39;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let’s try,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;= &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;b &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;= &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;== &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;b
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;false
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why wouldn’t &lt;code&gt;a&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;b&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; not equal? They are both empty right? Well, as developer docs says,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the operands are both objects, return true only if both operands reference the same object.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means a and b have different memory addresses unlike,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;= &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;b &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;= &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;== &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;b
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;true
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;where a point to b and equality is satisfied. In the case of primitive values like in the first
case, we have a different condition that says,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the operands have the same type, they are compared as follows:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;String&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;: return &lt;code&gt;true&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; only if both operands have the same characters in the same order.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Number&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;: return &lt;code&gt;true&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; only if both operands have the same value. &lt;code&gt;+0&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;0&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; are
treated as the same value. If either operand is &lt;code&gt;NaN&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, return &lt;code&gt;false&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Boolean&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;: return &lt;code&gt;true&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; only if operands are both &lt;code&gt;true&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; or both &lt;code&gt;false&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-problem&quot;&gt;The Problem&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; typeof new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;object&amp;#39;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and let’s try,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;== new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;false
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is known since both have different memory addresses and variables referencing different
objects do not satisfy equality. But then we can,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;= new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp; new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;= new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;true
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which to be frank, looks like an abomination but helps me spit this point. This essentially
means we have equality satisfied but at a very high cost. But why would this work when == 
doesn’t? Because we have a different algorithm for &amp;lt; and &amp;gt;. From developer docs,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, objects are converted to primitives using Symbol.ToPrimitive with the hint parameter
be ‘number’.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If both values are strings, they are compared as strings, based on the values of the Unicode
code points they contain. Otherwise JavaScript attempts to convert non-numeric types to
numeric values: Boolean values true and false are converted to 1 and 0 respectively. null is
converted to 0. undefined is converted to NaN. Strings are converted based on the values they
contain, and are converted as NaN if they do not contain numeric values. If either value is
NaN, the operator returns false. Otherwise the values are compared as numeric values.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; does is converting the date object to its numerical value, which is the
number of milliseconds between 1 January 1970 00:00:00 UTC and the given date aka the
epoch.* JavaScript use &lt;code&gt;Date.prototype.valueOf()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; behind the scenes to convert a date object
to a primitive value. But we can use &lt;code&gt;Date.prototype.getTime()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; since &lt;code&gt;Date.prototype.valueOf()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;
is usually called internally by JavaScript and not explicitly in code. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-solution&quot;&gt;The Solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we know what was wrong, and how we should actually equality check date objects&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2e3440;color:#d8dee9;&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;&amp;gt; new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#88c0d0;&quot;&gt;getTime&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;== new &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fbcbb;&quot;&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#88c0d0;&quot;&gt;getTime&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#81a1c1;&quot;&gt;true
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;that-s-it&quot;&gt;That’s it!&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is a weird programming language to learn, but it’s also a fun experience. So if you
decide to try it, like Veronika, I’d recommend you to play with its core, there is a lot to
explore. Thanks for reading!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Clubhouse Sucks</title>
        <published>2022-08-23T20:37:30+05:30</published>
        <updated>2022-08-23T20:37:30+05:30</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://ssiyad.com/blog/clubhouse-sucks/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://ssiyad.com/blog/clubhouse-sucks/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know what clubouse is, check out:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Clubhouse_(app)&quot;&gt;Clubhouse (app) - Wikipedia&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.joinclubhouse.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Clubhouse: Drop-in audio chat&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;inherent-problems&quot;&gt;Inherent Problems&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look back at social media platforms I been a part of, it makes me think if
clubhouse will ever be able to solve it’s inherent problems of being an online
platform. Provided, clubhouse is still in beta and registration is solely based on
invitation from existing users. Even then I saw an noticeable number of faceless
folk here and there. Don’t get me wrong, I very much promote anonymity in public
places, especially when it comes to online communities. But a platform which very
much boast it’s &lt;em&gt;real identity policy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, it seemed like the very opposite of
what the platform stands for. A few of them were even moderators of some really big
chat rooms where a lot of real people did not have the chance to speak.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quote Martin Garrix,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using social media to hurt and destroy is callous, acted out by cowards hiding
behind computers. My advice is to ignore negativity. Focus on the love around.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;clubhouse managed to fix this to a point, but not in a perfect way. Something like
strict verification using volunteers&#x2F;staff would have been a lot better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;freshness&quot;&gt;Freshness&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people I know praise clubhouse for it’s freshness. I don’t get it. As far
as I understand, clubhouse is a modern-podcast platform aka the voice chat. The idea
of podcasts are very well known and there are multiple instant messengers with voice
chat, like WhatsApp and Telegram. And there is numerous video-communication services
which is nowadays used by people all around the world to conduct meetings and stuff.
Heck, there is discord which is literally &lt;em&gt;clubhouse + numerous other features&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; like
text channels, roles and much more good moderation. You should give it a try if you
didn’t already. That being said, &lt;em&gt;clubhouse is old wine in new bottle&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. There is
nothing new as advertised.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privacy-or-anonymity&quot;&gt;Privacy (or Anonymity)&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be an important aspect of every communication medium in today’s world, or so I
believe. No one would know what happens in China if anonymity was not important.
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Arab_Spring&quot;&gt;Arab Spring&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; wouldn’t have happened. No news
of anything that ever happens in any &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Authoritarianism&quot;&gt;authoritarian&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
country will reach us. Anonymity is really a boon when it comes to real life. I understand
that it is sometimes a pain in the ass to control these trolls and whatnot, but it is
a price we pay for having platform where we can safely and courageously broadcast or
ideas. Without anonymity, I would have be jailed&#x2F;dead already, much like a majority
of people I interact with. In a modern world where criticism against governing bodies
are being suppressed with great strength, it is important to have such anonymous
friends to speak up certain things.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to privacy, I’d like if clubhouse does not tell my followers what I am
listening to, or speaking to, in their front page. I very much hate that. If I
participate in a discussion, it means I’m interested in it and does not mean I want
all my friends to let know I’m in such a discussion. It is even worse when anyone
could follow me and spy me like ever before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, I suspect if clubhouse have any preference for privacy or anonymity and I very
much hate that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;synchronicity&quot;&gt;Synchronicity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Wikipedia:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;synchronous: At the same time, at the same frequency&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost every online communication tool is asynchronous, and there is a reason for it.
Our &lt;em&gt;real life&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is very much different from our &lt;em&gt;online life&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, even if seems to be the
one and same. Let’s assume they are two threads in our program. &lt;em&gt;online life&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is fast
and you may loose many updates if you try to block it for even a little interval. &lt;em&gt;real
life&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; on the other hand is slow and you’re committed to it 100%.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.imdb.com&#x2F;title&#x2F;tt1375666&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Inception&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cobb: Well, dreams, they feel real while we’re in them right? Its only when we wake
up then we realize that something was actually strange.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like dreams, you engage too much in social media, you lose track of real life and start
to live in a very artificial -handpicked for you- mental state. This is why a lot of
social media platforms start as &lt;em&gt;asynchronous&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and starts to sync you in with constant
notifications. An &lt;em&gt;asynchronous&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; platform is where you start something, do something
else, come back and finish what you previously started. This enables you to engage in
both worlds while being a slave to neither.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as an exact opposite to this, clubhouse starts &lt;em&gt;synchronous&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and stay &lt;em&gt;synchronous&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.
You are expected to stay 100% committed to any event unlike &lt;em&gt;asynchronous&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; platforms
where you could take occasional breaks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also say, clubhouse success is a side effect of recent situations where a lot of
us are unable interact with the society around us, which leaves a big gaps in our
daily schedule and let us commit to things we disagreed to before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sound-as-a-medium&quot;&gt;Sound as a medium&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I very much like to listen to things, but I like to read more. So my views are biased
and may make no sense to you, beware. We all value our time. Me too. I’d love it when
people actually prepare beforehand and talk about about things clear and fair.
Unfortunately that’s not what I experienced from clubhouse. After all, we are all
common people and have our own weaknesses, but I’d rather listen to TED talk rather
than a clubhouse discussion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, it is impossible to re-read (or re-analyze&#x2F;re-listen) conversations,
unless you manage to record them, which I consider to be very unethical if you don’t
have permission from every speaker participating. Even if a re-reading&#x2F;re-listening is
possible, it will be very harder to cross reference than in case of text.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, me being an introvert, would like to participate in a way other than speaking, and
an absence of such feature makes me think if clubhouse is not for my kind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;does-it-really-suck&quot;&gt;Does it really suck?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think so. But in the end, it is just my opinion. Yours may differ and I’m perfectly okay
with that. I’ll encourage you to contribute more and more the society we live in. It
just feels that it is not for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
